Guide to the Walter Isard papers, 1938-1986.
Isard, Walter papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Walter Isard papers, 1938-1986.
3959
Walter. Isard
113.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, publications, financial records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Faculty and professional papers of Walter Isard (1919-2010), Economist and Peace Scientist. Includes records of professional organizations which he founded, including the Regional Science Association (RSA), Peace Research Society International and Peace Science Society International (PSSI).
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell professor of Economics (Regional Science and Peace Science) from 1979-2010. Also taught at Harvard, MIT and the University of Pennsylvania.
Founded the Regional Science Association (RSA) and Peace Science Society International (PSSI) and was the director and program chair for Economists Allied for Arms Reduction (ECAAR).
Graduated from Temple University (A.B., 1939) and Harvard (M.A., 1941; PhD, 1943)
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records related to Walter Isard’s career.
Material from professional organizations, especially the Regional Science Association and Peace Science Society International. Includes correspondence, administrative records, reports, and conference programs and papers, and publications such as the Journal of the RSA, Papers, and the Journal of Peace Science.
Records from his role as faculty at Cornell, Harvard, MIT and the University of Pennsylvania, including course materials and students' theses. Includes articles assembled for research, his notes, and drafts of his books and papers.
Includes alphabetized correspondence.
Also, a CD containing photos of Isard.
Commonly used acronyms/abbreviations include the following:
AEA: American Economic Association
ASSA: Allied Social Science Associations
ECAAR: Economists Allied for Arms Reduction (formerly Economists Against the Arms Race)
PEPS: Peace Economics and Peace Science (journal)
PRSI: Peace Research Society International
PSSI: Peace Science Society International
RSA: Regional Science Association
RSRI: Regional Science Research Institute
WAAS: World Academy of Arts and Sciences
WU: World University
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
The collection is arranged as follows. Please note that some boxes contain multiple series. Original folder titles have been retained.
SERIES I. THESES AND DISSERTATIONS:
Written by Isard’s advisees
Boxes: 1-5, 6, 46
SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE:
General professional correspondence, as arranged by Isard
Boxes: 11-16, 20-23, 42-44, 53-54, 64, 69-71, 77-78, 105, 109, 113, 119, 121
SERIES III. PROFESSIONAL ORGANIZATIONS, CONFERENCES AND INVOLVEMENT:
Includes correspondence, journals, conference materials, and administrative documents including memoranda, agendas, and financial records. Especially includes material from the Regional Science Association and the Peace Science Society International.
Boxes 1A-2A, 7-8, 17-20, 23, 27, 29, 36-39, 41, 45, 48-49, 51, 55, 58-61, 63, 71-74, 83-88, 93, 104, 108, 111, 113-114, 118
SERIES IV. RESEARCH, DRAFTS AND GRANTS:
Includes articles assembled by Isard for his research, his research notes, and drafts and manuscripts of his books, papers and presentations. Also includes materials related to research funding.
Boxes: 8, 10, 25-26, 28, 30-35, 40, 50, 52, 56-57, 59, 60, 63, 64, 66-69, 71-75, 79-83, 86, 89-90, 92-94, 97-103, 106-108, 110-111, 115, 117
SERIES V. TEACHING, ADVISING AND ADMINISTRATION:
Includes Isard’s correspondence with students, course materials such as syllabi, lecture notes, and material related to administration. This material is mostly from his time at Cornell, but also includes materials from Harvard, the University of Pennsylvania and MIT.
Boxes 8, 24, 31, 52, 60-65, 71-72, 74, 86, 90-93, 97, 109, 113
SERIES VI: ALPHABETICAL FILES:
Boxes of varying content, which alphabetized Isard by folder title. Including correspondence, research, professional materials, teaching/advising materials etc.
Boxes 9, 47, 112, 116, 120
SUBJECTS
Names:
Isard, Walter.; Liossatos, Panagis.; Chatterji, Manas, 1937-.; Azis, Iwan J. (Iwan Jaya), 1953-.; Leontief, Wassily, 1906-1999.; Peace Research Society International.; Peace Science Society (International).; Regional Science Association.; Economists Allied for Arms Reduction.; American Economic Association.; Allied Social Science Associations.
Subjects:
Physical geography.; Geography--Research.; City planning.; Regional planning.; Regional science.; Peace science.
Form and Genre Terms:
Resumes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Joseph Airov: Location Factors in the Synthetic Fiber Industry with Special Reference to Puerto Rico, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Thesis
- William Alonso: A Model of the Urban Land Market: Location and Densities of Dwellings and Businesses, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Gershon Alperovich: Regional Production Functions: Estimation and Comparison for the Nine U.S. Census Regions, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- David Bruce Berry: An Ecosystems Approach to the Preservation of Urban Open Space, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- David Frederick Bramhall: Integrated Techniques for Regional Projection and Policy Formation, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- David Edward Boyce: The Effect of Direction and Length of Person Trips on Urban Travel Patterns: An Examination of an Assumption of Urban Trip Distribution Models, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- David E. Boyce: The Effect of Direction and Length of Person Trips on Urban Travel Patterns: An Examination of an Assumption of Urban Trip Distribution Models (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Gerald A.P. Carrothers: Forecasting the Population of Open Areas: An Application to Regional Analysis of the Gravity Concept of Human Interaction, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Manas K. Chattopadhyay: Studies in the Structure of Calcutta Economy, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence with graduate student David, 26-Mar (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Hague A-B, 1961 (Box 1A, Folder 1)
  Regional Science Association
- Hague C-H, 1961 (Box 1A, Folder 2)
  RSA
- Hague H-M, 1961 (Box 1A, Folder 3)
- Hague S-L, 1961 (Box 1A, Folder 4)
- Hague S-Z, 1961 (Box 1A, Folder 5)
- Berkeley Institute R.S., Berkeley, 1962 (Box 1A, Folder 6)
- Lund A-G, 1963 (Box 1A, Folder 7)
- Lund G-L, 1963 (Box 1A, Folder 8)
- Lund L-S, 1962-1963 (Box 1A, Folder 9)
- Lund S-Y, 1963 (Box 1A, Folder 10)
- First Far East RSA, Tokyo A-G, 1963 (Box 1A, Folder 11)
- First Far East RSA, Tokyo G-L, 1963 (Box 1A, Folder 12)
- First Far East RSA, Tokyo L-S, 1963 (Box 1A, Folder 13)
- First Far East RSA, Tokyo S-Z, 1963 (Box 1A, Folder 14)
- Ghent, RSA conference D-A, 1964 (Box 1A, Folder 15)
- Ghent, RSA D-K, 1964 (Box 1A, Folder 16)
- Ghent, RSA conference K-S, 1964 (Box 1A, Folder 17)
- Ghent, RSA conference S-Z, 1964 (Box 1A, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1A, Folder 19)
  A-Z
- John Hammett Cumberland, The Location Structure of the East Coast Steel Industry with Special Reference to the Feasibility of an Integrated New England Steel Mill, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Robert Edward Coughlin, The Community Costs Resulting from Growth, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Robert E. Coughlin, Hospital Complex Analysis: An Approach to Analysis for Planning a Metropolitan System of Service Facilities, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Nasir G. Dossani, Duality Theories in Mathematical Programming-Their Implications for Regional Science, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Michael James Dear, Locational Analysis for Public Mental Health Facilities, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Gene Desfor, Binary Station Choice Models: An Examination of the Market Areas for the Suburban Stations on the Lindenwold High-Speed Line, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Masahisa Fujita, Optimum Growth in Monotone Space Systems, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Juan Carlos Gamba, Theory and Application of Dynamic Synthetic Potential Models, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Edgar S. Dunn, Jr., The Equilibrium of Land-Use Patterns in Agriculture: An Exercise in the Theory of Economic Location, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, Business meetings, June 1963- March 1965 (Box 2a, Folder 1)
- Philadelphia 1965 Peace Science Conference-Correspondence (1), 1965 (Box 2a, Folder 2)
- 1965 Philadelphia Peace Science Conference-Correspondence (2), 1965 (Box 2a, Folder 3)
- 1965-66 Peace Research Vienna Conference-Correspondence (1), 1965-1966 (Box 2a, Folder 4)
- 1965-66 Peace Research Vienna Conference-Correspondence (3), 1965-1966 (Box 2a, Folder 5)
- 1965-66 Peace Research Vienna Conference-Correspondence (2), 1965-1966 (Box 2a, Folder 6)
- 1966 Chicago Conference Peace Science (1) (Box 2a, Folder 7)
- 1966 Chicago Conference Correspondence (2) (Box 2a, Folder 8)
- 1966 Peace Science Chicago Correspondence (3) (Box 2a, Folder 9)
- Peace Science--Correspondence on dues & financial matters (Box 2a, Folder 10)
- Correspondence--Dues, publications (Box 2a, Folder 11)
- Correspondence 1972 A-Z, 1969-1972 (Box 2a, Folder 12)
- Peace Science Dept. Publication Information, 1974 (Box 2a, Folder 13)
- Becky--Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 2a, Folder 14)
  Rebecca Weiss, Secretary-Correspondence
- 1973 Cambridge Conf. Expenses PSSI (November) (Box 2a, Folder 15)
- Correspondence--Peace Research Society publications, dues (Box 2a, Folder 16)
- 9th N. American Peace Research Conference--Registration cards (Box 2a, Folder 17)
- PRS--Correspondence on Publications (Box 2a, Folder 18)
- PRS--Correspondence (Box 2a, Folder 19)
- Sung Woong Hong, Regional Interactions in the Theory of Multiregional Growth, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Douglas Jatem, Interregional Inequalities in the Process of National Economic Development, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Regional Randall Howes,Economic Analysis of Water Resource Development in the Susquehanna River Basin-An Application of Interregional Linear Programming, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Simon Hakim, Spatial and Temporal Relationship of Property Crime, Police Expenditure and Suburban Development, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Peter Richard Jones, Interpretations of Spatial Autocorrelation Statistics, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Robert Allyn Kavesh, Interdependence and the Metropolitan Region: An Extension of Input-Output Analysis, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Tatsuhiko Kawashima, Urban Production Function and Economies of Urban Agglomeration, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Sung Joo Kim, Multiplier Theories and Their Applications, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- John V. Krutilla, The Structure of Costs and Regional Advantage in Primary Aluminum Production, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Robert Eugene Kuenne, The Use of Input-Output Techniques for the Estimation of Employment in the Delaware Valley, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- John H. Larson, A Technique for Measuring the Effects of Industrial Growth on Municipal Revenue, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Ted Robert Miller, Cost Analysis of Regional Blood Blanking Alternatives, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Fu-chen Lo, A Two-Region Growth Model with Imperfect Mobility of Factors, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Jeffrey Platt, Residential Property Value Gradients and Urban Transportation Impact, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Atsuyuki Okabe, Contributions to the Study o Stochastic Spatial Interaction Models, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Anthony J. Mumphrey, Jr., Evaluating Public Facility Alternatives for Equity and Efficiency Goals, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Eliahu Romanoff, A Metropolitan Input-Output Model and the Demand for Urban Space, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Carl Peter Rydell, The Shape of Optimal Consumption Paths in a Two-Region, Single-Sector Economy, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Adam Zachary Rose, A Dynamic Interdisciplinary Model for the Economic Analysis of Air Pollution Abatement in New York State, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Walter Isard and Robert Coughlin, Municipal Costs and Revenues Resulting From Community Growth, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Michael B. Teitz, Regional Theory and Regional Models, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Luc-Normand Tellier, An Interaction Probability Density Approach to Human Gravity, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Tappata, Appendix (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Heber Nazareno Tappata, A General Framework to Relate Spatial and Economic Variables, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Tabbata, Chapter 10 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Benjamin H. Stevens, Interregional Linear Programming, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Foh-strang Tang, Detection and Estimation of Transportation Impact with Models of Suburban Residential Property Sales Prices, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Tony Edward Smith, Contributions to the Foundations of Measurement Analysis, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Kamal Salih, A Policy Framework for Regional-National Development Planning: A Study in the Theory of Political Space-Economy, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Eugene William Schooler, Regional Advantage in the Production of Chemicals from Petroleum and Natural Gas, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Abdo Ovadia Salama, Stochastic Control and Multilevel Coordination Models for Air Quality Management Within a Region, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Franklin Victor Walker, An Estimate of Growth in the Texas-Louisiana Gulf Coast Area, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Walker II (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Chin Ming Yang, Impact of a Rapid Transit Line on Suburban Vacant Land Values, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Thomas Vietorisz, Regional Programming Models and the Case Study of a Refinery-Petrochemical Synthetic Fiber Industrial Complex for Puerto Rico, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Vietorisz, Report Including Nylon (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Koji Ueno, On the Dynamics of Regional Economies, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Hamilton C. Tolosa, Growth Poles: A Study in the Economics of Spatial Concentration, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- RSA Officers, 1958-64 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- President, V. Pres., Provost, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2a)
- Procedures, Meetings of Peace Research, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 2b)
- Brochures, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 3a)
- Regional Science Dept. Annual Report, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 3b)
- Graduate Group in Economics, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 3c)
- University--General, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 3d)
- GSAS Dean's Office, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 3e)
- Representatives, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 3f)
- Argentine Section, 1967-1969 (Box 7, Folder 4a)
- Australia, New Zealand Section, 1963-1970 (Box 7, Folder 4b)
- Brazil RSA, 1964-1967 (Box 7, Folder 5a)
- British Section, 1963-1968 (Box 7, Folder 6a)
- British Section, London, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 6b)
- Canadian RSA, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7a)
- Chilean Section, RSA, 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 7b)
- Czech Section, 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 7c)
- Dutch Speaking Section, RSA, 1961-1970 (Box 7, Folder 7d)
- Ethiopian Section, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 7e)
- Europe, NW-Multilingual, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- French language RSA, 1960-1965 (Box 7, Folder 9a)
- GDR section, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 9b)
- German language groups, 1961-1971 (Box 7, Folder 10a)
- German R.S. Institute, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 10b)
- Ghana Section, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 11a)
- Greek Section, 1961-1966 (Box 7, Folder 11b)
- Hungarian Section, 1965-1969 (Box 7, Folder 11c)
- Hungarian Academy, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 11d)
- Calcutta meetings, 1965-1972 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Indian RSA, 1967-1971 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Israel Section RSA, 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 14a)
- Israel Section, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 14b)
- Italian Section, 1963-1971 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Japanese Section, RSA, 1963-1971 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Korean Section RSA, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 17a)
- Mexican Section RSA, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 17b)
- Philippine Section, 1963-1974 (Box 7, Folder 17c)
- Polish Section, 1962-1970 (Box 7, Folder 17d)
- Portuguese Section, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 17e)
- Romanian Section, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 18a)
- Scandinavian Section, 1961-1968 (Box 7, Folder 18b)
- SE Asia Section, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 18c)
- South African, 1965-1968 (Box 7, Folder 18d)
- Spanish Section, 1960-1963 (Box 7, Folder 19a)
- Turkish Section, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 19b)
- USSR Section, 1963-1967 (Box 7, Folder 19c)
- West African Section, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 19d)
- Yugoslav Section, 1960-1968 (Box 7, Folder 19e)
- Faculty Senate, U of Penn (Box 7, Folder 20)
  Faculty Senate procedures and manual
- Austin, Murray, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 1a)
  dissertation proposal
- Bilecki, 1973, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 1b)
  Notes
- Blair, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 1c)
  Correspondence on student
- Booth (Box 8, Folder 1d)
  Douglas Earl Booth-Thesis outline notes, CV
- On the Conduct of RSA European conference, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 1e)
- South East Asia and Related international programs, U of P, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- N.E. Section of RSA, 1963-1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Midwest Great Lakes Meeting April 18-19, Midwest RSA, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 4a)
- Midwest Section RSA, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 4b)
- Southeast U.S. Section RSA, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Western Section RSA (Box 8, Folder 6)
- PRS (I) Financial Statements, see also box 38, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 7a)
- Peace Research Society (I) Other Business (Box 8, Folder 7b)
- Correspondence Malmo Meeting 1963 (Box 8, Folder 7c)
- British Section (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Central European Section PRS (I) (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Czech Section, PRS (I) (Box 8, Folder 10a)
- East Asia Section PSSI South Asia (Box 8, Folder 10b)
- Finnish Section, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 10c)
  PRS (I)
- German Section PRS (I), 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 10d)
- Hawaii Section, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 10e)
- PRS (I) Poona Conference 1969--and correspondence with Indian scholars (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Israeli Section, 1968-1972 (Box 8, Folder 12a)
- Japanese Section, PRSI (Box 8, Folder 12b)
- Korean Section (Box 8, Folder 13a)
- Polish Section, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 13b)
- Scandinavian Section PRS (I) (Box 8, Folder 13c)
- Midwest Peace Research (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Southern Section PRS (I) (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Western Section PRS (I) (Box 8, Folder 16)
- St. Louis Bi-Centennial (Box 8, Folder 17)
  Notes, correspondence (PRS)
- Syllabi--coursework MIT, 1950's Penn and other items (Box 8, Folder 18)
  Course material
- Isard and Schooler--"Location Factors in the Petrochemical Industry w. Special Reference to Future Expansion in the Arkansas-White-Red River Basins" (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Research papers on local and regional industry by Isard and S. Czamanski, G. Karaska, E. Romanoff (Box 8, Folder 20a)
- Military expenditures from an early paper (Box 8, Folder 20b)
  Research data
- NASA Report (Box 8, Folder 20c)
- Research (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Research study--Isard, Langford, Romanoff; "Philadelphia Region Input-Output Study Working Papers, Volume II" (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Research study--Isard, Langford, Jr.; "Philadelphia Region Input-Output Study Working Papers, Volume IV", Jul-68 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Research study--Isard, Langford, Jr.; "Philadelphia Region Input-Output Study Working Papers, Part III, Final Demand" (Box 9, Folder 3)
- U of Penn Budget Proposals, 1956-1959 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Record of Academic Salaries Inside--Regional Science Dept. & Resources for the Future, 1955-1963 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- U of Penn Budget Proposals, 1959-1963 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- U of Penn Budget Proposals, 1963-1967 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- U of Penn Budget Proposals, 1966-1969 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- U of Penn Wharton School Regional Science Graduate Program 1970's (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Regional Science Institute (Box 9, Folder 10)
- RSRI--correspondence, finance, 1967-1974 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- RSRI, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 12a)
- BHS--RSRI understanding (Box 9, Folder 12b)
- Czamanski & Karaska Papers 1965, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Dept. of Regional Science--Faculty meetings, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 14a)
- Regional Science--Program and Instruction (Box 9, Folder 14b)
- Dept.--Business, 1964-1969 (Box 9, Folder 14c)
- Graduate School GSAS--correspondence, forms, memos, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 14d)
- Gravity Models Course (Box 9, Folder 14e)
- Course outlines--Econ dept. (Box 9, Folder 15a)
- RS 601-602 (Box 9, Folder 15b)
- RS 625 (Box 9, Folder 15c)
- RS 621, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 15d)
- RS 623 (Box 9, Folder 15e)
- B.A. Reg. Science Techniques in Business (Box 9, Folder 15f)
- RSI (11-12), 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 16a)
- Reg. Sci. Dept.--U of Penn 1960+ (Box 9, Folder 16b)
- RS 621, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 16c)
- Research statements--Department (Box 9, Folder 16d)
- Dept. of R.S.--forms, memos,etc. (Box 9, Folder 17a)
- R.S. Dept. Fellowship Committee, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 17b)
- EPA-Air Pollution, Cornell #1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- EPA-Project RSRI (Box 10, Folder 2)
- NASA-Progress Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- NASA-Miscellaneous, 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- NASA- Grant (1), 1963-1967 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- NASA-Grant (2), 1962-1967 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- NSF-Transport. Costs, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- NSF- R.S.R.I. Grant (Box 10, Folder 8)
- NSF-Undergraduate Program, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- NIH- Public Health, 1961-1967 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- NIH- General, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- NIH- N.I.C.H.D., 1972 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- NIH- Isard/Dacey, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- NIH-Miller, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- NIH-Air Pollution, Isard-Harvard (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Economics of Water, 1965-1969 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Economics of Water (2) (Box 10, Folder 17)
- ESSA-Continental Shelf (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Resources for the Future, 1965-1970 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Transportation-Rose, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 20a)
- FELS (Margolis), 1970 (Box 10, Folder 20b)
- Ford Foundation-1962 Proposal, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 20c)
- Ford Professorship Committee, 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 20d)
- Ford Foundation, Ylvisaker, 1955-1959 (Box 10, Folder 20e)
- Ford Foundation-Harkary-April 1961, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Guggenheim, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 22a)
- NSF Research Evaluation, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 22b)
- U of Penn Budget Proposals, 1967-1973 (Box 10, Folder 23)
- AB 1947-1949, 1947-1949 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- CD 1946-1949, 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- EF (1946-49), 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- GH (1946-1949), 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- I J (1946-1949)- Journal of Political Economy correspondence), 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- KL (1946-1949), 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- MN 1946-1949, 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- OP 1946-1949, 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- QR 1946-1949, 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- ST 1946-1949, 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- UV 1946-1949, 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- WXYZ 1946-1949, 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- MISC. including bibliography of papers of WI 1951, resume of WI 1947 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- 1966 Committee to select Poly Sci Dept. Chairman, Univ. Of Penn, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- U. of P. Faculty Corres. (Wharton) 1959-1966, 1959-1966 (Box 11, Folder 15a)
- Mailing List of WI's Paper (Box 11, Folder 15b)
- Dept. Material--Regional Science-University of Penn., 1964-1966 (Box 11, Folder 15c)
- MSSB 1970 I, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Preface-Japanese translation, Methods, Oct 1968, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 17a)
- Isard and Stevens--Dynamic L.P Inter (Box 11, Folder 17b)
- Electronics Sections I (Box 11, Folder 17c)
- Summer 1947 Personal Correspondence, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- AB 1949-1951, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- CD 1949-1951, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- EF 1946-1951, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- GH (1949-1951); I, J 1948-1951, 1948-1951 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- KL 1949-1951, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- M 1949-1951, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Correspondence to Phil-A.E.A., 1951 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- NO 1949-1951, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- PQ 1949- 1951, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- RS 1949-1951, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 28)
- TU 1949-1951, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 29)
- VWXYZ 1949-1951, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 30)
- T.H. Tung--Projections of Textile/Electronic Industry for Philadelphia SMSA to 1985-2010 (Box 11, Folder 31)
- Corres. With Dr. Isard 1960, 1960-1967 (Box 11, Folder 32a)
- Ford Foundation, 1955-1962 (Box 11, Folder 32b)
- Day Planner 1949-1951, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 33)
- Correspondence 1963, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1960-1961, 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 2)